好的， 这里有些关于我的信息，你们在讲座后可以查看一下
all right so this is some stuff about me go check take a look at this later
最后一页有幻灯片的链接，你们之后可以看一下
I've got my slides linked at the very end the last slide so you can check that out later
我们会讲到React组件模式
we're going to be talking about react component patterns
如果你在推特上关注我的话，你会知道我讲了很多组件模式相关的内容
and if you follow me on Twitter you've probably heard me talk about component patterns a lot
这也解释了我为什么对组件模式这个话题感到如此兴奋
and so this is kind of justifying why I'm so excited about component patterns
以及我觉得学习组件模式对你来说是个好主意
and why I think it would be a good idea for you to go learn about them as well
我的声音有点哑是因为昨晚的卡拉OK
if my voice is a little hoarse it's because karaoke last night
我玩儿的很开心， 我小时候真的很喜欢林肯公园乐队
I had a great time yeah yeah Sooni learned that I really like Linkin Park as a kid
我本来打算带着大家一起做深蹲。 如果想和我一起深蹲的人说一声woop
so I was gonna do air squats say woop if you want me to do air squats
人不够多。 但是保持身体健康很重要
that wasn't enough so but physical health is really really important
尤其对做我们这行的人来说。 深蹲有助于大脑和思考， 所以不要像我一样跳过
and in our industry it helps your brain it helps you think so don't don't skip them like I just did now
Bennet Ben带着你们做了，所以我们没问题
Bennet Ben's got you taken care of so so we're doing ok
我刚介绍了我演讲的内容
so just to give you kind of an overview of what we're talking about
我喜欢在演讲之前做个简介，然后你再决定是听讲还是刷推特
I like to start my talks out with expectations so you can decide whether you want to be on Twitter or not
我会讲到一个典型的组件的生命周期
and so we're gonna be talking about a typical life cycle of a component
这跟你想的不一样，这是一个故事
this isn't what you're thinking, this is a story
我会讲到一些模式，应用这些模式来简化组件
I'm going to show you some patterns that you can use to simplify this component
我会讲到组件的可组合性，然后给你们留一个作业
and we'll talk about composability and I'll give you a challenge
这个演讲不是教你如何实现模式
this talk is not how to implement these patterns
我后面的幻灯片会有些资源教你如何去做
I have some resources toward the end of my slides to you on how you can implement some of these patterns
这个演讲也不是关于特定的工具和库，但我会快速提一下
and it's also not about a couple things that I just wanted to give a quick shout-out to
我觉得你们应该了解react testing library和Downshift
because I think you should know about the react testing library woo and downshift
我提到的这些模式都是在我开发Downshift的过程中学到的
for sure downshift yeah downshift is where I learned pretty much all of these patterns in the process of building downshift
如果你正好需要一个类似自动完成的输入框，你可以看一下Downshift
so take a look at that if you're looking for an autocomplete or a drop-down kind of an enhanced input
Babel插件宏
Babel plug-in macros yeah
你们在想，Babel插件是什么鬼
okay so everybody's like what is Babel plugin?
create-react-app V2会内置Babel插件宏，所以你该了解一下
you know so create-react-app at version 2 will have this built in, so you want to learn what Babel plug-in macros is all about
这个演讲不是关于glamorous(作者开发的css工具)，因为已经作废了
this is also not about glamorous because that was deprecated
也不是关于emotion，但你该用用emotion。感谢Kai(emotion作者)
but it's not about emotion either, but that's what you should use emotions. great Thank You Kai
好的，我们开始吧。 这是演讲中涉及的组件
all right. let's jump into it. here's the component that we're going to be walking along and learning about
这是个折叠菜单，你可以展开条目，很酷
it's an accordion, so you can open up these different items in the accordion. it's kind of cool
让我们想象一下，有人给了你这个设计你开始开发
so when you, let's pretend for a second, that you were tasked with building this - they gave you this design
设计师说需要能够展开条目和关闭
and they said we want to be able to open these different things and close them
每一条里面都有内容，这有一个手的图标，当内容展开是会转换方向
and at each one of these has contents we have this hand that we want to turn direction based on whether it's open
然后你说，太好了，我喜欢用react开发
and so you say great and you are like I'm loving this whole react thing
我可以把state放在这里，用户点击的时候更新state
I can put my state right in there and I can update the state when they click on it
真是太简单了。你的API是这个样子的
it's so easy and your API for this thing looks like this
关于样式我加了一条笔记但是没人问起它
I added a note about the theme and font so nobody asks me about it
这是Sara Dresner。 我用了这个样式，每个人都喜欢，太好了
but yeah so that's Sara Dresner and I created this theme that everybody loves, it's awesome
这个样式的名字叫猫头鹰。Phil **，我不记得他的姓了。不对，字体是叫dank mano，很棒的字体
and called night owl and Phil and I can't say it's last name I'm sorry is dank mano so that's the font and it's awesome
于是你开发好了这个组件，你非常开心
okay so you built this component and you're super excited
因为它将所有的逻辑封装了起来。这是有人过来说：
because it encapsulates all this logic and then somebody comes around
嘿，你的组件很酷，我想在我的项目中使用它
and says hey that is a really cool component there I would like to use it
你说：太好了， react让我们能够做到组件的复用
and you say awesome is it that cool with react we can do this
他们说： “但我们有一个不同的用例， 我需要内容在上面展开”
and they say yeah but I have a different use case I need things to be rendered above
“你能让内容在上面展开吗？” 你说，可以没问题
can you make it render above and you say yeah sure
我可以加一个条件判断在这儿，让内容在上面展开
we'll just have consumed conditional logic here and to render the contents above
再加一个条件判断来改变图标小手指的方向
I have some conditional logic for the hand that direction that it's pointing
而用户需要做的只是加一个above=true，很简单对吗
and all it's going to take is for you to add above equals true, so easy right
如果你想尽量简洁，你可以不管JSX v2的规范，你可以直接写above就可以了
and if you want to be super terse and you don't care about JSX of version 2 then you can just say above all by itself
而不用写above=，还能更简单嘛
and you don't need the equals true how easy could it be
然后你自我感觉良好，你开发了以个组件，并且开始有人使用它了
and so you're feeling pretty good about this like you've built something people are starting to use it
然后有个人过来说：嘿，我看到你的改动了，现在可以支持向上展开和向下展开
and then somebody says hey I saw how you changed it so it could support above and below
但我需要向右展开，你觉得可以吗？能做吗？
I want it to support the contents on the right tabs on the left is that is that a cool thing, can we do that
你说，可以，当然了。只要加上right=true，和条件判断
and you say yeah sure we can do that just right=true and now we just have some conditional logic
我们需要重写一点样式，之前我们用flexbox，我们打算用css grid
we have to rewrite it a little bit because it was flexbox before and now we're going to do CSS grid
css grid autoflow column就可以了。这样就实现了，太神奇了。谢谢你css grid把一切变得这么简单
grid autoflow column and now like magic it's so easy Thank You CSS grid for making that easy to do
你开始感到有些不自在，因为render方法变复杂了
and you're starting to get a little uncomfortable because this render method is getting bigger
并且添加功能的过程中加了一些条件判断
and I have some conditional logic as you're adding these features
为了让自己感觉好些，你加了一些测试。当然你用的是react testing library
you have to add some tests to feel comfortable with with things and of course you're using react testing library
但即使这样，你还是感觉有点不舒服
but even with that you're starting to make you feel a little uncomfortable
同样的情况又发生了，有人过来说， 嘿，我看到你支持向右展开了，能支持向左展开吗？
and of course somebody comes to you and says “hey I noticed you could do right can I also do left?”
你说，可以的，left=true， 问题解决了
and you say yeah sure just left is true and and life is good
David Kay，弹钢琴的人教导我们
and then David Kay course she'd yes David Khursheed Kay piano man
他说如果right和left同时为true的话会怎么样呢？
he reminds you that hey this this is like impossible states we got left is true what if I did right is true as well what happens now?
于是你重构了一下，每个人都很开心
and so you refactor it while you rewrite it and everybody's happy about this
你把条件变成了position=left，你提供了一个position的枚举列表，一切都很美好
you change position equals left so now you got an enum so every everything's good
这里有个小经验，使用枚举列表来解决冲突状态的问题
so there's a little lesson use enums don't don't make pot impossible states possible
现在大家都很高兴，感觉很棒
so now everybody's happy with that they're they're feeling pretty good
接下来，又有个人过来找你，而你已经不太满意目前的render方法了
so the next thing that happens is somebody comes to you and you're feeling pretty uncomfortable about this render method
render方法越来越大，然后有人过来
it's getting pretty big and somebody comes to you in years
他先说：嘿，你的组件很酷
the first thing that they say is like hey that's really cool
你说，停，你是让我改什么吗？
and you're like wait what stop do you want me to change it?
他们说，是的。你问：改什么？
and they say yeah yeah and you're like okay okay what is it
他们说，render方法没问题。你松了口气然后问，那需要改什么？
and they say well, the way that it renders is fine and you're like oh good okay so wait what do you want me to change?
他们说，可以一次只展开一条吗？
well the logic with how I can open all of these at once?
我想让用户每次只展开一条，你能做到吗？
I actually only want to be able to open one at a time, is that something you can do
你说：应该可以吧，我不动render方法
and you say yeah I guess so like I leave my render method as it is I don't need to touch that
我只需要改click事件的回调方法
I just need to touch like or deal with the code that's handling the click here and so
好的，在这里加一个if语句就可以了
you say okay just a little if statement to make that possible
现在我们可以每次只展开一条了，还不赖
and now we can only open one at a time that wasn't that wasn't all that bad
在组件上加上single=true，可以，没什么大不了的
now we have the single true and that's that's fine no big deal
之后又有人过来说，嘿，我注意到可以修改组件的状态
and somebody comes to you again and says hey I noticed we can actually change the state
我这有个存在很久的bug，我们不允许用户关上所有的条目
I've had this like bug for a long time people shouldn't be able to close all the items
我希望的效果是，用户可以展开任意多的条目，但是关闭只能剩一个
I need to like they can open as many as they want but they can only close down to one
也就是每次至少有一条是展开的。你说好吧，能做到
so only one or one has to be open at all times so you say okay yeah I can make that happen
click的回调函数这里，关闭条目时至少留一条是展开的
I click here it doesn't actually close can only close down to one at a time
这就避免关闭了，好了
and that's prevent close it's true okay yeah
于是你的render方法里有一些条件判断
so now you have a bunch of conditional logic in your render method
你在click回调函数里也有一些条件判断
you've got some conditional logic in your click Handler
还不是太糟，但你开始觉得不舒服了
it's not too bad but you're starting to feel a little uncomfortable about this
然后又有人过来说， 嘿，我想把一次展开所有条目和只能关剩一个结合起来用
and then somebody comes to you and says hey you know how like that single wanted open at a time
可以吗？我可以一次展开所有但是不能关闭吗？
can I combine that with opening only one eye so I can only open one at a time but I can't closd it
能实现吗？你说，可以的能实现
is that is that possible and you say yeah that's that's possible we can make that work
所以我不能关掉这个，并且每次只能打开一个。你就同时用这两个开关就可以
so I can't close this and I can only open one at a time you just use both of the prompts and so you're so happy
这个功能不费力就实现了
because just naturally out of nowhere that actually it's supported
然后你就想，太好了，我再也不用作出任何修改因为它支持世界上所有的用例了
and so you're like oh sweet I don't have to change anything ever again because it supports all the use cases in the world
然后另一个人看了你的代码，用了你的组件，然后说
and then somebody is looking at this and they're playing around with it and they say
“嗯，点击条目展开内容”
huh we got something we click on, and then it shows some contents.
“每次只显示一项内容。。。这看上去像是个不同的组件”
it only shows one at a time, that looks like a different component that I need to build
“你能增加一个选项把UI显示标签页的样式吗？”
how about a tabs UI one at a time constant yeah yeah can we make it tabs of this?
你不想这样，你说不行，我的render方法已经很复杂了
you either this and you say no my render is too complicated already
然后他们说，“不，听着，这仅仅需要加一个if语句” 你说，“之前别人也是这么说的”
and they say no listen listen it is just an if statement and you say I've heard that before
“永远不会只是一个if语句的”
it's never just an if statement
他们说，不，我保证只是一个if语句。在你render方法的开头，判断if(this.props.tabs)为真，返回this.renderTabs()
they say no listen I promise it's just so at the top of your render method if this.props.tabs, return this.renderTabs
然后把tabs有关的逻辑都放在renderTabs方法中，我不会动你的render方法的，很简单
and we'll put all that logic for the tabs rendering in a different method and I won't have to touch the rest of your render method so it'll be so easy
你意识到能持续交付你的组件很重要, Michael告诉我们需要持续交付。我相信他
and you know you need to ship stuff right we need to ship stuff Michael Chan told us this morning you just got to ship and I believe that so
我们现在支持了tabs，但是你内心深处感觉被背叛了，你很伤心
we'll have a tabs problem but inside you're feeling like somebody's betrayed you and sad
然后又有人过来说：“嘿， 我能把内容向上展开吗？” 你这次说不
and then somebody comes and says hey could I render those tabs above and that's when you really say no
于是他们复制粘贴了你的代码并做了修改，现在每个人都很伤心
and they copy and paste your code and make it tabs component and now everybody's sad
因为到处都是重复的代码，但是你持续交付了，这点还不错
because you have duplicate code all over the place but you're shipping so that's good
我的重点是，持续交付是最重要的，比所有我今天教给你的东西都重要
so I really want to drive home that the importance of shipping is like it's more important to ship than to do all the things I'm going to teach you
但是如果我们可以在持续交付的同时不讨厌自己写的代码呢？
but what if we could ship and not feel terrible our code at the same time
这就是我要讲的主题。我们探索一下
that's what I'm going for here so let's extrapolate this a little bit further
我想你们应该明白这个故事的中心思想了，永远都会有新的需求
I think you're getting the idea. this does not stop ever
于是你不断的增加逻辑，像之前那样，改变你的api来支持新的功能
so you continue to add things like you're changing your data to map to to your features of your accordions
基本上这意味着更多的属性。disabled=false 我们有一个开放的标题了
so these are basically more props. disabled is false now we have an open title
我们在已有的props中新加一个open触发器
and we have this like the props that we had before but now we have an open trigger
如果你想聚焦时展开内容，失焦时关闭内容，应该怎么做呢？
what if you want to open on focus and close on blur
或许我们可以在标题和内容上分别应用不同的样式
and then maybe we have a title classname and a contents classname so we can customize the styling
然后现在我想在用户触发时运行一个分析的脚本
and now I need to know when the users triggering so I can fire off analytics
classname open和close
and the closed classname open classname
这是我最喜欢的东西之一，任何以render开头的属性是我最喜欢的属性
and here's one of my favorites anything that's prefixed with render is my favorite prop
renderExpandAllButton方法渲染奶牛当手指向上方
renderExpandAllButton rendered cows when the sign is up
就是说是什么都没关系，因为我们对渲染的过程没有任何控制权，并且你想复用这段逻辑
like whatever it is there because we don't have any control over rendering and you want to share this logic around
你还会有这些专门用于渲染的开关
you're gonna have these render specific prompts
这就是为什么这个问题这么严重的原因，它不仅仅是让你感到挫败，一次次的修改你的组件，组件也变得糟糕
so here the reasons why this is a problem beyond just like feeling frustrated yourself and always having to come back to this accordion that's getting worse and worse
组件打包后体积变大，性能下降。最开始我们写了个简单的折叠菜单，只有30行
bundle size and perf take a hit so initially we made like this 30 lines accordion component that was so simple
代码很简单，之后为了支持所有的用例，代码增加到了200到500行
and it's pretty small but now to support all of these use cases it's grown to 200 or 500 lines of code
而在你的应用中，你并不需要所有的用例，你只需要30行代码的实现
and in your app you don't like need that you need 30 of those lines
所以如果可以tree shaking组件就好了
so like if you could tree shake code within a component you would do that
但组件没法tree shaking所以你交付了大量的代码，但其中大部分用户并不需要
but you can't so you're shipping a ton of code to your users that you're never actually using
也许应用中其他模块会用到，也许根本不会用到
and in addition to that like maybe other parts of the app are using it but maybe entirely different apps are using it
他们成了你用例的受害者。so they're suffering for your use cases as well
还有代码维护的问题，维护这样的代码可不好玩
and then maintenance overhead this isn't like not really very fun to maintain
你需要写文档，回答用户关于所有props用法的问题
you have to worry about documentation you have to worry about answering people's questions about these different props that you're supporting
因为基本每个属性支持一个特定的用例，每次有新用例出现，你就加了一个新的属性
because they're all really kind of single use case specific and you add a new prop to every single use case that people come up with that you haven't thought of before
代码很难维护。开发的难度增加同时更容易出现bug
and so it's not fun to maintain. implementation complexity increases and that has an correlation with bugs that enter the code base
开始有人给你提交代码，肯定会有人提交他们用例的代码不是吗
so as people come in to contribute which of course you're going to have other people contribute their use cases right
因为你自己再也不想碰这些代码了
because you don't want to touch it anymore
但是他们开发时需要搞清楚所有已经支持的用例
but they have to learn about all the use cases that are already being supported
贡献代码变得更难，并且更容易出现bug，因为现在组件变得如此复杂
so it's harder to contribute and bugs sneak in a lot easier because this component is so complex
组件的接口也变的无比复杂，关于接口我最忍受不了的是
and the API this is probably my biggest beef with this props explosion that we're seeing here
你需要给每个属性加上文档，每个人在用你的组件之前需要了解每个属性
is you have to document each one of these prompts and everybody who comes in to use your component has to read every single one of those prompts
他们才知道每个属性是不是必须提供的，这不是什么好玩的事
to figure out whether those props are necessary for their use case and that is not fun
你给的例子永远是过期的，因为有新的属性可以更好的实现同样的功能
the examples are always out of date because now there's this new prop that does this better
于是每个人都很伤心
and so this all this just makes everybody sad and highlighted so now there we go
当我为准备这次演讲时，我在推特上做了个调查，你们可能有人参与过
so when I was researching for this talk I asked Twitter some of you may have responded
你用过的哪个组件有最多的props？
what is the reusable component that you've used that has the most number of props
获胜者是有60多个属性的组件，是开源的
and the winner was a 60 prop component that's open source
我不会说出它的名字因为这么做不太地道
I'm not going to name names because that would be mean
但是这个组件有60个属性，并且有些叫做"选项"，“配置”的属性
but it has 60 props and then there are some props that are specific like like options prompts
你骗不了任何人，这意味里面包含了更多的属性
which you're not kidding anybody those are just more props
“选项”属性中有30个可选项，等同于你加了30个属性到你的组件里面
it's like this object that has like 30 options like yeah you just added 30 props to your component
有个叫Jen的人回复了我的那条推特，说：“我把这叫做属性爆炸”
for all intents and purposes and somebody responded to that tweet and said her name's Jen Creighton I call that and a prop clips
谢谢Jen，通过创建一个新的标签让世界更美好
yeah Thank You Jen made the world a better place with a new hashtag
如果我告诉你之前展示的所有功能只用37行代码就可以实现呢？
so what if I told you all of those demos that you saw were built on the same 37 line component
支持所有的用例，但是只有37行代码
that supports all of those use cases in 37 lines
让我们来尝试下快速实现这些功能，使用37行代码
go ahead really quick try to implement the whole thing in 37 lines
好的，完成了吗？我们来看一下，做的好
okay are you done okay let's take a look good job
我不希望你过多关注具体实现
so I don't want you to focus too much on the specific implementation here
但是实现中运用了两种模式，带来了灵活性和简单性
but there are two patterns that exist in this implementation that enable this kind of flexibility and simplicity
我们会看如何更多的使用这个组件，首先我们使用了渲染属性模式
and we're going to look at how to use this component more but here we're using render props
这个模式最近在社区里非常流行，你可能也听说过
which have really taken steam in the community you've probably heard of them
通过渲染属性传递一个函数，我们直接调用它，并且将我们的状态和更新状态的逻辑传递过去
it's this stop props in we're just calling that as a function we pass it our state and a mechanism for updating our state
由用户决定他们想渲染什么内容
and now people can render whatever they like
我们还使用了state reducer模式，这个也许你不熟悉
and then we're also using a state reducer which is one you might not be familiar with
这个模式，使用户能够在状态更新前得到通知，并且能够修改将要更新的状态
and that enables users to change the state as it's being updated so it can modify how the state updates happen
这两种模式都是“控制反转”的实现
so both of these patterns are actually implementation of the concepts called inversion of control
“控制反转”的意思是，有些工作我们本来是交给库去完成
and what that basically means is normally with the library you're going to call into the library
就像你调用render方法渲染一个react组件
like you're gonna call to get to render a react components or something
控制反转是你使用的库反过来调用你的代码
inversion of control is where the library calls back into the user code
就像库对你说，“嘿，我要做这件事了，你想让我怎么做？”to say hey I'm going to be doing this thing, what do you want me to do about that?
你可以修改，我们看一眼demo
and you can make modifications to it so let's take a look at a demo
谢谢Eva开发了codesandbox，有人喜欢用codesandbox吗？
Thank You Eva's for codesandbox. who loves codesandbox?
codesandbox是最酷最酷的东西了
yeah this thing is the coolest the coolest thing
好的，这是我们的折叠菜单和基本折叠菜单，这是它的代码
okay so here's our accordion and our bass accordion is that component that you saw earlier so this is our implementation that builds out our accordion
对于基本折叠菜单，我们接受一些条目然后将剩下的props展开以便可以覆盖其中的一些属性
so with the bass accordion we're just accepting some items and then we spread the rest of the props so we can override some of the accordion or bass accordions prompts
于是折叠菜单的用户可以重写一个基本的折叠菜单属性
so the user of accordions and override the basic accordions props
然后我们将一个函数作为children传过去，或者使用渲染属性
and then we're providing our children as a function or our render prop
在children函数中我们得到了索引和条目
and that's taking our open indexes and our handle item quick
从这开始就完全是我们的责任了
and from there on out it's totally our responsibility
之前的API比这难用多了，对吗？
so this is actually a significantly like more difficult to use API than this right?
用户写的代码更多了，这就是控制反转
you have a lot more work to do this is what inversion of control is
让你有控制权同时有更多的责任
it's giving you control and responsibility
但是通过复合组件模式，你可以像之前那样使用折叠菜单组件
but because of reaction composition model you can actually now I can use this accordion like I used that first accordion
这是调用accordion，传给他一些条目，很酷的是我用复合组件模式来创建它
it's just call accordion. pass it some items and the cool thing about this is that I can use reaction composition model to create that
然后我可以添加更多的逻辑来支持所有的用例
and then I can keep adding more logic to this accordion to make it support all the different use cases we're talking about
同时一点不改基本折叠菜单组件
without making any changes to the basic accordion
这个做法很整洁是因为，如果新的折叠菜单组件如果不支持之前的用例
and why that is neat is because if this accordion doesn't support the use case that I have
我可以直接拷贝这些代码来自己写一个
I can just go copy all of this code and go make my own implementation
复制粘贴这种代码要不之前好多了，因为这些代码里没有逻辑
and this code to copy is actually pretty pretty straight for there's not a lot of logic going on
而且一共才37行代码，复制粘贴也不会让你觉得难受
and it's it's less painful to copy and in an accordion example like the accordions 37 lines
downshift的代码要远远多于37行
downshift for example is a lot longer than 37 lines of code
所以它里面有更多的代码可以复用，我们还可以复制这个特定的渲染逻辑
and so there's a lot more code that we can share there and then we can duplicate this specific rendering
这样就可以实现我们特殊的用例
so that we can have our specific use cases
之后比如说又有个同事过来说
so anyway let's say I build this thing and then the coworker comes and says
“嘿，Kent, 你的折叠菜单很酷，不过要怎样才能让内容向上展开呢？”
hey that's a pretty cool cool accordion you got there Kent what can I do about having it render the contents above the button
你说：“只要把emotion组件放在这里，这些只是加了样式的组件”
you say literally just take these emotion components these are just like style components like styled components kind of thing
“把这些组件移动到这里，完成了”
just take these components and move them and you're done
不算完成，因为小手图标的指向是错的
yeah you're not quite done because this emoji is pointing the wrong way
于是我们就让它指向上方，搞定了
so we'll just point up and now it's planes right way
这是Alfred，如果有人想知道，Alfred太酷了
that was Alfred somebody's going to ask me that was Alfred so cool
然后又有人说，我想把内容向左边展开， 可以了
and then somebody says hey I want to render it on the left - right
你回答说，这个菜单项是个emotion组件，这个组件仅仅是关于样式的，是用CSS grid实现的
then you say hey this accordion item is an emotion component that's like total style concern we're using CSS grid over there
所以如果你把方向改成水平它就会用css grid
so if you change direction to a horizontal then it's going to use CSS grid
加上grid: autoflow你就能让内容向着你想要的方向展开了
egg and grid autoflow column and now you can have things rendering the right direction
这里我们让小手指向这个方向，指向右
so here we'll move this hand pointing this way and then we'll have a whoops a point right
完成了，很酷是吧？
and tada! cool. right?
然后又有人说，等一下等一下，这是很酷，但我想让内容向另一边展开
and then if you want there's a like hold on down a hold on that's pretty cool but I need my contents on the other side
没问题，完成了
yep tada
接下来我们只需要将图标移到那边，当你能控制render方法时这很简单
and then we'll just move those emoji over there it's pretty easy when you have control over rendering right
你有控制权，可以做任何你想做的
you literally are in control, you do whatever you want to
你想要在标题里加上个hello？随便加
you want to have a little thing that says hello in the title it's all yours feel free
你想用有样式的组件代替emotion？可以
you want to use styled components instead of emotion?
或者你想用普通的css，都可以，权利在你手中
you want to use regular CSS that like all of that power is in your hands
这就是控制反转的威力that's the power of inversion of control
回到刚开始，有人过来跟你说：
so going back to our original when some that person comes to you and says
“嘿，我想要render的逻辑有些不同，我不能通过渲染属性实现”
hey I need the logic to be different now like I can't do that with the render prop
你说：“这就是我支持state reducer的原因” 我们有这个叫做single的函数，只有3行代码
you say that's why we have a state reducer so we have this three line function called single
我们来快速看一下它的代码
I wasn't going to show you but I'm gonna show you really quick single
在这里。哦我错了，是4行代码，我应该提前检查一下
single, there it is. okay it's four lines. I was wrong, I should have reviewed first
4行代码的函数，参数是当前状态，状态的改变
four line function that just takes your state, your changes
如果状态的类型是opening，我们就将open的索引改成只有一个
and if the state type is opening then we're going to change the open indexes to only have the one
防止关闭的功能也是类似的实现方法，如果点击关闭时我们有多于或者少于一个菜单项是展开的状态，就不会允许状态变成关闭
and then our prevent closed works in a similar way if we're closing and we have more than or less than one that are already open then will not allow that closed to happen
我们在这加一个state reducer然后将single函数放在这儿，这就可以了
so with that we can add a state reducer and we'll put single here and that's all it takes
借用昨天一些内容。很酷，太简单了
to borrow something from shortly yesterday. so cool. that's pretty easy
这就是防止关闭的实现，酷
well what about prevent close cool
现在我不能关闭这个菜单项，但是我可以展开多个，然后这个就可以关闭了
now I can't close this one but I can open multiple and then I can close this one
只要写点简单的js就可以将这些功能结合起来，就可以做到结合reducer和防止关闭
yeah and then to combine those it's just some more a little bit of JavaScript here that will prove combined reducers single and prevent close
我同时支持两个功能，我不能全部关闭，可以同时开多个。酷
and I would get both of those functionality I can't close it and I can open it. cool.
好，现在利用这种组合模式，我可以实现标签页组件
right so now with reacts composition model I can actually create a tabs component
封装好这些reducers，这样作为标签页的用户我不需要再考虑这些了
to kind of encapsulate those reducers so I don't have to think about those reducers as a user of the tabs component
于是现在你有了这个基本的标签页组件传递结合的reducer里面包含single和不允许关闭所有的逻辑
so now you have this basic tabs that passes combined reducers for single and prevent closed
如果你想，你还可以开发自己的state reducer传给组件，实现更多可定制的内容
and the state reducer that you can provide if you want to so you can even add more customization on the base tabs if you want to
很不错。我们把这些应用在标签页组件中
so that's pretty neat. let's go ahead and well use that in our tabs
我们有基本标签页组件让我们渲染成标签页而不是折叠菜单
here we have base tabs so let me render tabs instead of the accordion
现在我们有标签页组件了
and now we've got our tabs tada
这里我们创建一个基本标签页组件就像在折叠菜单中用到的一样。谁明白为什么呢，我们甚至都没有用类实现
and here we're using base tabs just like we use the accordion but as far as we're concerned like who knows what's going on we're not even using class components here
这一切只是react的复合组件模式
it's all just react beautiful composition model we've grown to love
使用标签页组件时。我们接收这些条目，map他们，得到按钮和菜单内容
and so here with tabs we are accepting those items we map over those for both the buttons as well as the item contents
如果之后有人过来说 嘿 我希望按钮在下面，我们在做那种类似ios的风格
and then when that person comes along and says hey I want the buttons to be below, the contents we're doing some sort of iOS fake thing
所以我们希望按钮在下面，是吗？so we want the buttons below right
tab item组件只是一个emotion组件，我们再把position设定为above
and then this tab item is just an emotion component and so we'll say the position is above
这就会改变这个动画，让它指向正确的方向
and that will change that animation so it animates the right way
实现这些功能我根本需要对base accordion做任何修改
and with all of this we didn't have to change our base accordion at all
tabs组件的用户不需要关心它的实现，实际上tabs的底层复用了折叠菜单
and as far as the tabs is concerned we don't know that it's using the accordion under the hood
因为折叠菜单支持这些用例，tabs封装了实现的细节
because the accordion actually supports that usecase and tabs can kind of abstract away that implementation detail
封装性是我们如此热爱React的一个原因，谢谢
which is one of the reasons we love react so much is because we can do that so thank you guys
我在egghead和frontendmasters上有关于高级React模式的课程
so I promise you resources if so I've got this advanced react component patterns course available on egghead i/o and front-end masters
如果你完全不懂React，我在egghead还有一个免费的初学者课程，你可以从这个课程开始学习
if you're brand new into react my beginner react course is available for free young egghead so start with that first
你可能会迷路，享受吧
and you'll probably get lost here feel free but yeah
在结束之前我想提醒你们一下
before I wrap up I just want to give you a word of caution
如果说一开始是你在开发这个折叠菜单
so what if you're building this accordion component we're taking going back to the future or back in time for a second
而你知道所有的模式
and what if this is all that you know that you need right now
但是你不知道将来会出现什么用例
you don't know of the future potential use cases
你该从一开始就开发这些灵活的功能吗？should you implement all of these flexible features right from the get-go?
我建议不要
my suggestion is probably not
今早，Michael Chan讲到了如何实现一个完美的Modal.js支持所有的用例
this morning Michael Chan talked about how you were he suggested making that modal j/s and you're like this is going to be the end-all be-all of modal's
我的建议是，不要想着解决世界上所有的问题
my recommendation is don't assume that you're going to solve the world
因为这只是浪费时间
and don't try to solve the world because you're going to waste a lot of time
这个比喻不太好。我们应该致力于让世界变得更好
that metaphors messed up. we should be working to improve the world right sorry
但你该懂我的意思。解决一些你该解决的问题
but hopefully you get my gist. try to solve the problem that you're intending to solve
然后停下来，交付你的软件。当新的需求出现时
and then stop and ship it and then when additional use cases come up
这时你才需要考虑，好吧，怎么做才能让它更灵活，以便应对未来需求的变化
that's when you start looking into okay how can we make this more flexible so we can support not only the new use case but a lot of other use cases that are coming out
你不会需要它，你应该尽量删掉你的代码
you ain't gonna need it you should be optimizing for delete ability
因为所有东西最终都会消失殆尽
because everything eventually will be erased from existence
换句话说，听Michael的，他是个非常聪明的家伙
in other words listen to Michael smart smart dude
我给你们的挑战是，应用这些模式来简化你的API
they're so my challenge to you is to use patterns that simplify your API
我们讲到了state reducer, 受控属性，供应者模式
we talked about some of these state reducers, control props, the provider pattern
非常高兴react内置了对context的支持（useContext）
which I'm so glad is built-in to react now with the context
复合组件模式，渲染属性模式
compound components, render props,
很酷的是，我们不断的重新发现
the cool thing about software is that we're constantly rediscovering
重新发现一些老原则，像是很多60 70年代我们已经知道的模式，用来解决当前遇到的问题
old principles that they knew like in the 60s and 70s and applying them to today's problems
有很多类似的模式。像控制反转，并不是新的发明
and that's all lots of these things our inversion of control is not a new concept like we didn't invent that
我们只是将控制反转应用到react组件开发上，这对我来说很兴奋的事情
we just applied that to react and that's what's really exciting to me
我希望过一段事件我再做这个演讲时，幻灯片上会加上更多的模式
so I would love to in years time give this talk again and be able to put a lot more patterns on this slide
我给你们的挑战是，重新发现更多的模式
so my challenge to you is to go rediscover more patterns
我的演讲结束了，谢谢大家
that's all for me. thank you!